I...
Pino.
Is anyone here?
Anyone?
Pino?
Where is everyone?
This place is...
Vince!
Pino!
Pino?
Who are you?
Welcome...
to the land of the rising sun.
You complete my fate
The world unwinds inside of me
The halo crawls away
You refill my place
Come and save me
Believe in me and drink the wine and take my hand and fill me up
Golo presents
Come and save me
We are in Haros?
When I arrived,
you had collapsed and were unconscious.
I brought you here.
Collapsed?
I'm sorry.
I am Kazkis Hauer, the master of this tower.
You must be confused as to what's going on
since you've only just woken up.
Excuse me, but did anyone else survive?
That'd be improbable.
Come over here.
I'll give you a sweet.
She's an infected autoreiv.
An autoreiv?
She's mechanical.
A machine...
Pino!
Sorry.
She seems to be shy around strangers.
She supposedly has the mind of a child,
but acting like that after you saved her...
I guess I don't understand her.
But why did you help us?
Because you are a friend of mine.
"Friend"?
All those who know the ends of the earth are friends.
"The ends of the earth..."?
The world you saw, and the world you see.
Those eyes of yours look upon death.
That might be true.
After all, survival...
will mean seeing much more death.
My companions died as well.
I've been alone ever since.
But why?
Why was I the one who survived?
It was fate.
I'm impressed you've come this far.
Hop, hop, jump.
Hop, jump, jump.
Ow, oww...
Land of the rising sun, huh.
It's been a long time since I've seen a view like this.
Pino.
What's the matter?
Take a look.
It's almost like a maze.
Hey!
What's the matter?
Come!
What is it?
What are...
these?
Why...
are they here?
Let's go back to the ship...
to the rabbit,
Vince.
I don't like this place.
Let's get out of here.
I'm scared.
We can't stay here.
Let's go together.
Let's go look for the rabbit.
Are you just going to sit there?
I'm going to go alone!
But...
he helped me.
Do you want some too?
Um, no thank you.
You haven't touched your food.
Those autoreivs...
Oh?
Oh, you mean the Knights?
You were at war with Haros?
You killed many in Haros...
So?
Conflict inevitably creates a victor and a loser,
as well as life and death.
The conflict wasn't started in ignorance of that.
But what reason was there to continue attacking Haros?
Conflict is meaningless.
However, there is meaning in destruction.
You saw Haros' end, didn't you?
You saw Senex, no?
Senex...
It destroyed Haros?
Why are you obsessed with Haros?
They were in need of purification.
And that's why you were fighting them?
Of course not...
Left behind during the long sleep, they sought meaning.
To deny the truth of their abandonment...
they found meaning in seeking each other's destruction.
The world eventually descended into chaos.
As their will weakened, even death lost its meaning.
To think of them as free-willed in the first place
is simply ludicrous.
Ill-fated ones...
No, we should beg forgiveness as well.
I should,
as should you.
I should?
H-Hey, wait a minute.
What have I done?
I've done nothing, and yet I'm always being chased by something.
Now, I've ended up here.
That's why, isn't it?
Not doing anything, not able to do anything.
It's painful...
I was that way as well.
You too?
I despised myself for not being able to do anything,
and I was haunted in my sleep
by the ceaseless verbal abuse from my other self.
Without meaning, time passed by.
And to survive that... pain...
I've felt the same pain you have.
"The same pain you have"?
I feel that I could come to love you...
the way I loved Senex.
You loved Senex?
I'll tell you our story.
If my Asura is the sun, Haros is the moon.
Senex and I each built a tower that mirrored the other
as proof of the vows we were to
exchange on the eventual Day of Awakening.
Do you understand what I'm talking about?
Realizing our tragic fate, Senex and I suffered,
yet also gained love.
But before we could make those vows, Senex died.
You killed her.
No...
But that's fine.
Before fate, vows are but fragile things.
Instead, I think it fortunate that I was able to meet you.
I thank your strength.
What are you saying?
What?
I killed her?
Her?
How could I have?
What are you saying?
Senex was-
Please stop!
You are...
I don't know anything!
You're joking with me, aren't you?
Aren't you?
What does she have anything to do with me?
Please.
Tell me it's true.
What are you?
You...
are supposed to suffer as I do.
Are you going to make me suffer?
Why?
I don't know anything!
Has he lost his memories?!
He killed, unknowing?
He killed my Senex.
Why...
This is my Asura's true appearance.
You saw this, didn't you?
It's just a monument.
Asura's residents must've made it
to record Asura's former glory for posterity,
but it was useless.
What happened to Asura's residents?
They all perished.
They were destroyed by the Knights.
What?!
Haros and Asura were one.
Their residents died due to conflict, and only the Knights remained.
Then...
Haros' soldiers were...
They were a lie.
Merely a lie returned to nothingness by death.
But...
they were alive!
Once alive, people have no choice but to continue living.
"People", hm?
Right now, I am happy, for all life has ended.
Why?
Aren't you their master?
You are a fool.
Having lost your memories, have
you also lost the ability to see the truth?
I have my memories!
Then who are you?
Try telling me who you are.
I am Vincent Law.
I was working in Romdeau's Control Division.
but I was placed under suspicion of treason,
and fled from the dome.
And before that?
I was in the Mosk dome.
I was an immigrant.
What were you doing in Mosk?
What was I doing?
You don't remember, do you?
Despite your vague memories, you've
managed to live without any doubts until now.
Isn't that definitive proof that you
deliberately erased your own memories?
Erased memories?
You said you were in Mosk, no?
Yes.
It is my homeland.
I see.
It was Monad, wasn't it.
You gave him your memories, didn't you.
But when you absorb another's memories,
you're unable to bear their sheer volume.
Even so, he accepted them.
He must have loved you.
But by showing you his love, Monad lost you.
No, not just Monad...
You also lost yourself.
To erase your memories is to lose the very essence of who you are.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying that you are a traitor.
A traitor?
Since when?
You fled...
in a way that brings utmost shame to a PROXY.
"PROXY"?
But what I find even more unforgivable...
is that without your memories,
you killed my beloved Senex!
I am the proxy of brilliance,
Kazkis PROXY.
I swear on my honor that I will eliminate the traitor.
What's the matter?
Even after erasing your memory and losing your self,
you still have your instincts, don't you?
Thinking that, I find those who live on
the path of insanity all the more endearing!
Senex...
I'll go insane as well, with my memories of having lived with you!
Sorry, sorry...
Did that hurt?
Hop, hop, hop!
Rabbit!
What is... this?
My arm!
Help me!
It hurts!
Am I a monster?
No...
I am...
You are a PROXY.
"PROXY"?
I wonder what this feeling is...
You disgust me...
I feel as though I may vomit.
Yes, that's right...
You...
I'll let you name yourself for the last time.
What are you the proxy of?
You cannot answer?
Then die!
Flee!
But you are already within a trap!
Both you... and I!
Ninety-eight rabbits.
Ninety-nine rabbits.
One hundred rabbits!
Okay!
I already counted to one hundred, so
I'm going to leave Vince behind, okay?
Fifty more!
One hundred and one rabbits!
One hundred and two rabbits!
One hundred and three rabbits!
This is worthless.
It lacks fragrance.
This one is also worthless.
Too acidic; low class.
There are no good ones left...
only rejects.
Please tell me.
What are the PROXY?
Why are you asking, after erasing your own memories?
Am I a PROXY?
Why must I fight?
Then why did you come back?
You wish to kill me, don't you?
No.
Time has awakened.
I don't want to harm anyone!
Then...
who killed Senex?
Was Senex the only one you killed?
You've lost both your mission and your
loved one, so why do you still try to live?
Why don't you die here?
Senex...
I would've liked to have seen you again in life.
I shall avenge your death.
I did not...
wish this...
Why...?
I ask you...
once again...
what are you the proxy of?
My name is...
Ergo PROXY...
the proxy of death.
I see.
May you suffer.
All those who wander the darkness
seek the light.
But when you reach the light...
you avert your eyes from the brilliance.
You even feel pain.
It is the same with truth.
One day, your eyes will be scorched by the light that is truth,
and know eternal darkness.
That is your judgment!
Senex...
Am I not human?
Then...
how am I to live?
Four hundred...
rabbits...
Vince!
Pino...
Did you get hurt?
No...
No, it's not my blood.
Oh, it's the other one...
The other Vince, the one who's not you.
Welcome back!
You...
knew?
Let's go to Mosk.
Weren't you afraid?
Of me?
Afraid?
But you always save me.
I see.
Although I can't see anything,
I've begun to move...
from the moment the two of us leapt out of Romdeau.
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
Can't help seeing, saying, and hearing.
See no evil, speak no evil, and hear no evil.
That is the grown-ups' lullaby.
Oh?
meditation  existence
But where am I?
Hey, hey...